dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
Neji's Judgment
(マツリ)これを差し上げます。
力を貸してください。
I'll give this to you,
so please, help me!
(ネジ)そんなものはいい！
それより案内を頼めるか？
Don't worry about that!
Can you just show us the way?
はい！
Yes!
あちらです。
Over there.
白眼！
Byakugan!
とらえた！
Found them!
(リー)どうするつもりです？
無視はできない。
What are you planning to do?!
We can't ignore them.
(テンテン)でも 中忍試験を
降りることになっちゃうかも。
But that could mean defaulting
on the Chunin Exams.
す すみません。
I-I'm sorry.
お前のせいではない。
俺自身の判断で行動している。
It's not your fault.
It's my decision to take action.
あっ はい。
R-Right.
テンテンの言うとおり→
You're right, Tenten.
今回の中忍試験を
棒に振ることになるかもしれない。
This could mean a default
on the Chunin Exams.
だが こういうときアイツなら→
But in a situation like this,
he wouldn't...
ナルトだったら
迷わずこうするだろう。
Naruto wouldn't hesitate
for a moment to act.
ええ！ きっとね。
そうですね。
Yes, I'm sure he wouldn't.
You're right!
目の前の困ってる人を
放っておいて→
Naruto would scold us if
we ignored someone in need
二次試験を通過したとしたら
ナルト君に叱られてしまいます。
in order to pass
the Second Exam.
ナルトも 我愛羅も運命に挑み→
Naruto and Gaara both
challenged their destinies
困難を乗り越えた者同士だ。
and overcame hardship.
けして ひと事だと
片づけたりはしない。
They wouldn't turn their backs and
say it's someone else's problem.
♪♪(琵琶)
(我愛羅)
ったく 来るなと言ったはずだ。
Damn it... I told you not to come.
(フウ)だからって
放っておけないっす。
How can I stay away?!
アンタの友達がここにいたら
きっと助けに来たに違いないっす。
If your friend was here,
I'm sure he'd come to save you.
友達…。
Friend?!
ああ アイツは バカだからな。
Yeah, that's because he's a fool...
うおっ！
ぐあっ！
うぅ…。
あっ！ う…。
あぁ…。
うぅ…。
忍法 コクーン。
Ninja Art: Cocoon...
《ホウイチ : 何だ？ あれは》
What is that?
これは…。
アッシの力じゃ→
This is...?
My power. But it isn't enough
to break this chakra chain.
このチャクラの鎖を
ぶっちぎるのはムリっす。
だから せめて
時間を引き延ばしてみるっす。
So, I'm going to try
to buy us some time.
♪♪(琵琶)
《これは…。
This is...!
チャクラの鎖の動きが鈍くなってきた。
The flow in the chakra chain
is becoming sluggish...
あの繭には チャクラの吸収を
抑える力があるというのか？》
That cocoon has the power to suppress
the absorption of chakra?
何をした？
チャクラの糸で繭を作ったっす。
What did you do?
I made a cocoon with
my Chakra Threads.
アッシの繭は メッチャ細いチャクラの糸が
複雑に絡み合ってるっす。
My cocoon is
a complicated tangle of
super-fine Chakra Threads.
思ったとおり 吸収する力が
弱まったっす。
And it weakened its absorption,
just as I thought.
止まったわけではない。
It didn't stop it.
確かに チャクラの吸収スピードが
遅くなった分→
The rate of chakra being sucked out
has definitely slowed down,
体は楽になったが→
and lessened the pain...
このままでは
いずれ尾獣を抜かれ→
But eventually, our Tailed Beasts
will be extracted...
死ぬ。
and we'll die.
マイナス思考はダメっす。
Negative thoughts aren't good.
今にきっと誰かが
助けに来てくれるっすよ。
I'm sure someone will come
to save us!
お前こそ なぜ そこまで
プラス思考になれるんだ。
How can you be so positive?
生まれつき おめでたいって
褒めてくれた人がいるっす。
Someone once praised me
that I was born special.
誰も助けにはこないだろう。
No one will come to help us.
そんなことないっす。
Don't say such things!
お～い！ 誰かいるっすか？
Hey! Is someone out there?!
繭がある分 声は通らない。
Your voice won't travel
through this cocoon.
うっ… しまった。
Oops! Damn it.
こうなったら
力ずくでも抜いてみせるっす!!
All right then...
I'll just pull this out
with brute strength.
は～っ！ この… くっ…。
よっ… よっ… あれ？
やっぱり 救援を待つっす。
We'll have to wait
to be rescued, after all.
いくら待っても
砂隠れの援軍は来ない。
No matter how long we wait,
no one from the Sand
will come to our aid.
またまた… マイナス思考。
Again with those negative thoughts!
俺たちを襲っているのが
砂隠れの人間だと言ってもか？
Would you still say that
if you knew
the person attacking us
is from the Sand?
マジっすか!?
Are you serious?!
《フン… ムダなことを。
How futile.
むしろ それで
逃げ場をなくしてるだけだ。
All you did was throw away
any way of escape.
いつまで
閉じこもっていられるか》
Just how long do you think
you'll last in there?
♪♪(琵琶)
かつて俺にとって
他者との関係とは→
In the past, the only way
I could relate to others
憎しみと殺意でしかなかった。
was with hate and a desire to kill.
だから 俺が風影になったことを→
Now that I am the Kazekage,
いまだに
恐怖による支配だと感じ→
some believe that
I will rule through fear,
亡き者にしようとする者がいても
それは それで しかたがない。
and are trying to eliminate me.
That can't be helped.
(我愛羅)否も応もない。
I'm the one who brought it on.
自らが招いたことだからな。
ただ一つ 心残りがあるとしたら→
If I have any regrets,
it's only that I wish people knew
今の俺が
変わろうとしていることを→
知ってほしかった
ということくらいだ。
how much I was trying
to change.
苦しみや悲しみ 喜びを
他者と分かち合えるって→
That friend of yours
taught you, right?
That you can share and
understand the pain,
あの友達から
教えてもらったっすね。
suffering and happiness of others!
ああ そうだ。
Yes, that's right.
しかし 人柱力にとって
それは難しいことだ。
But it's difficult for a Jinchuriki.
そんなことない！
きっと大丈夫っすよ。
That's not true!
I'm sure it'll all work out.
人柱力だって
きっと 100人の友ができるっす。
Even a Jinchuriki can make
a hundred friends.
里長が そう言ってたっすよ。
I just know it!
The Village Chief told me so.
《似ているな やっぱり》
They're alike, after all.
(ガイ)砂隠れの慌てぶりを見ると→
Judging by the panic within
the Hidden Sand,
やはり我愛羅は 彼らの庇護下には
ないと思うべきだな。
we can assume they don't have
Gaara under their protection.
(紅)ええ
恐れていたとおりの事態に。
Yes. This is just as we feared.
(アスマ)自らをオトリにしてクーデター派を
あぶりだそうとしているのか…。
He set himself up
as bait to lure out
the faction planning
the coup d'état.
(ガイ)ヘタをすると すでに
暗殺されている可能性もあるな。
In the worst case, it's possible
he's already been assassinated.
彼は 木ノ葉とも友好的だけど→
The Leaf has close ties to him.
そんなことになったら
今後の関係にも影響が出るかも。
If something like that happens,
it would greatly affect
our future relationship.
暗殺などさせるものか。
We can't allow him
to be assassinated.
でも誰がクーデター派か
定かではない以上→
As long as we don't know
who the coup d'état faction is,
砂隠れに協力は求められないわね。
we can't go to the Sand
to request assistance.
我々だけでも なんとかするぞ。
We'll just have
to do something ourselves.
とはいえ どこに消えたか
何の手がかりもないからな。
That being said,
we don't know where he went.
We have no clues at all.
あれは！
What's that?
(ガイ)うむ 砂隠れの下忍だ。
Ah, they're genin
of the Hidden Sand!
♪♪(琵琶)
あの琵琶の音！
The sound of a lute?!
♪♪(琵琶)
あっ！
何ですか あれは！
What is that?!
It looks like a giant cocoon!
なんだか 大きな繭みたい。
それに あの男は何者でしょう？
And who is that man?
あなたたちは
滝隠れの受験者ですね。
You're exam participants
from the Hidden Waterfall!
(ケゴン)ああ。
はぐれたフウを捜しに来た。
Yes...
We're looking for Fuu.
She wandered off.
はぐれた？
Fuu wandered off?
《ネジ : なに!? 我愛羅とフウから
チャクラが抜かれている》
What?!
Chakra is being extracted
from Gaara and Fuu.
どうしたの？ ネジ。
What's wrong, Neji?!
あの繭の中には何が!?
What is in that cocoon?!
２人の人柱力だ。
Two Jinchuriki.
１人は我愛羅様だけど
もう１人はいったい…。
One of them is Lord Gaara...
But who's the other one?
滝隠れの… お前たちの仲間だな。
From the Hidden Waterfall...
It's your teammate.
いいのか 今のままでは
あの２人は死ぬぞ。
Are you fine with this happening?
At this rate, they'll both die.
あの琵琶法師の封印術だろう。
It's probably the Sealing Jutsu
of that lute-playing priest.
２人の尾獣チャクラは吸収され→
He's extracting Tailed Beast Chakra,
いずれ
その本体まで抜かれてしまう。
and ultimately,
the Beasts themselves.
えっ 尾獣を抜かれたら
我愛羅様のお命が。
If the Tailed Beast is extracted,
Lord Gaara will die!
お願いします 助けてください。
Please help him!
お前たちは どうするつもりだ。
And what do you intend to do?
仲間を見捨てる気？
Are you going to abandon
your teammate?
ここは いったん 休戦して
ともに戦おうではありませんか。
Let's call a truce,
and fight together!
今なら まだ助けられる。
If we act now, we can save them...
頼む…。
(ヨウロウ)フウを助けてやってくれ。
Please...
Save Fuu.
ああ。
All right.
そうか。
I see!
(ネジ)確認したところ
ヤツの背後は見通しがよさそうだ。
From what I gather,
the priest's back is vulnerable.
そこで 作戦を考えてみた。
This is what I've come up with.
俺たちは 攻撃チームと
救出チームの二手にわかれる。
We'll divide into two teams...
An attack and a rescue team.
攻撃チームは
ヤツの背後から静かに近づき→
The attack team will sneak in close
and attack from behind...
攻撃を仕掛けて その隙に
救出チームが２人を助ける。
The rescue team will seize
the opportunity and rescue the two.
リーとマツリ 滝隠れの２人は
あの琵琶法師を。
Lee, Matsuri and the two
from the Hidden Waterfall
will attack the lute-playing priest!
(ヨウロウ/ケゴン)わかった。
(リー)はい 僕に任せてください！
– Understood.
Right! We'll pulverize him!
私も救出チームに…。
I'd like to be on the rescue team!
いや 救出チームには テンテンが必要だ。
No, I need Tenten for the rescue.
２人で 救出に向かう。
オーケー。
The two of us will go.
Okay!
(ネジ)散！
Scatter!
《手裏剣影分身》
Shuriken Shadow Clone!
《水遁 水手裏剣》
Water Style: Water Shuriken!
《必殺 宝具流星》
Deadly Shell Meteorite!
木ノ葉旋風！
Leaf Hurricane!
法力結界 チャバシラ！
Dharma Barrier:
Celestial Pillars!
なんだ あれは？
防御の術か？
What is that?!
Some defensive jutsu?!
いえ それだけとは思えません。
No, that's not the only thing.
気をつけてください。
えっ!?
Let's use caution!
テンテン チャクラ刀を頼む。
Tenten, I need a Chakra Sword.
了解！
Got it!
SWORD
ハッ！
《繭の一点を狙って！》
Aim for a section of the cocoon!
ここだ！
Right here!
ハッ！
クソッ！ ヤツには近づけん。
Damn it! We can't get close to him!
強力な結界だ。
It's an impregnable barrier!
これでは 我愛羅様のために→
At this rate, we're not helping
Lord Kazekage at all.
何のお役にも立っていない。
いえ これでいいんです。
え？
No, this is sufficient.
What?
敵の気を引きつけ
ネジの仕事をやりやすくするのが→
Just drawing his attention away
will make Neji's job easier.
僕たちの役目なんです。
That is what we are here to do.
ネジ 大丈夫？
Neji, are you all right?!
２人とも大丈夫か？
Are you two okay?
やっぱり 救援が来てくれたっす！
See!
Someone came to help, after all!
他言は固く禁じてあったのだが…。
I gave strict orders
not to tell anyone...
部下を叱るなよ。
Don't be angry with
your subordinates.
お前のことを
心から心配してのことだ。
They were worried sick about you.
(ネジ)やはりな。 この鎖は
点穴を正確に貫いている。
I figured as much...
This chain has penetrated
your Chakra Points.
経絡系への直接的ダメージに加え→
And they are causing direct damage
to the Chakra Network.
点穴により
チャクラの流れをコントロールし→
They're controlling
the flow of chakra
through the Chakra Points and
お前たちの中の尾獣チャクラを
吸い取っているんだ。
siphoning away
your Tailed Beast Chakra.
ああ。
いずれ尾獣チャクラが弱まれば→
Yeah...
Eventually, the Tailed Beast Chakra
will be weakened enough
その本体までもが
抜かれてしまうだろう。
and he'll extract the Beast itself.
なんとかしてほしいっす。
Can you please help?
尾獣チャクラとはいえ チャクラはチャクラ。
Tailed Beast or whatever,
chakra is chakra.
鎖に尾獣チャクラを吸い取られている
点穴を突くことで→
If we plug the Chakra Point that's being
used to siphon the Tailed Beast Chakra,
その流れを止めることが
できるかもしれない。
we may be able to stop the flow.
できるか？
Is that possible?
ああ。 確信はないが
やってみる価値はあるだろう。
Yeah... It'll be tricky,
but it's worth a try.
頼む。
Please do.
ここだ。
Here it is!
柔拳 点穴針！
Gentle Fist: Chakra Point Needle!
どうした？
What happened?
あぁ…
尾獣チャクラの勢いが強すぎて→
The Tailed Beast Chakra is
so powerful that it repelled me.
弾き返された。
尾獣チャクラが これほどの力を
持つものとはな。
I didn't think it would
be this strong!
《ネジ : あのとき ナルトの中の
九尾チャクラの凄まじさに→
That time...
The force of the Nine Tails Chakra
inside Naruto was unbelievable...
驚いたものだが…。
我愛羅とフウの尾獣チャクラも→
So I guess Gaara and
Fuu's Tailed Beast Chakra
ナルトの九尾チャクラに
勝るとも劣らない…。
are just as powerful as Naruto's.
というわけか》
頑張ってほしいっす。
Please don't give up!
We're counting on you!
頼りにしてるっすよ。
あぁ わかった。
Yeah, I know. I'll try again!
もう一度…。
はぁ～っ！
よし 止まったぞ。
あぁ。
All right, the flow stopped!
次は お前だ フウ。
うん！
You're next, Fuu!
Okay!
(ネジ)はぁ～っ！
♪♪(琵琶)
《なに!?
What?!
尾獣チャクラの流れが止まった。
The chakra flow has stopped?!
なぜだ？
尾獣チャクラが流れてこない》
Why?!
Why isn't the Tailed Beast
Chakra flowing in?!
琵琶法師の様子が…。
えぇ。
The lute-playing priest
is acting strange...
Yes, something must
have happened.
何か起こったんでしょうか。
あの木ノ葉の白眼
何かやったのか？
Did the Leaf's Byakugan user
do something?
うむ…
明らかに敵の様子がおかしい。
Well, the enemy definitely
looks flustered.
これは いったい…。
What's happening?
まるで 生きているような…。
不気味な…。
It looks like it's alive!
That's creepy!
気をつけてください！ うっ…。
Be careful!
《このままでは この鎖は
吸収するべき尾獣チャクラを探し→
Unless I do something,
the chain will continue searching
for Tailed Beast Chakra!
すでに俺の体内に溜め込んだ
尾獣チャクラを狙い→
It will find the chakra that
it has already stored up in me...
奪い合いを始め 崩壊する》
and start siphoning
that Tailed Beast Chakra...
until it destroys itself.
結界が破られた!?
The barrier's been broken!
うっ…。
ぐわ～っ！
彼を殺してはならない。
頼めるか？
May I ask you, not to kill him?
ああ わかった。
Yes, I understand.
うう…。
ネジ。
Neji...
(ネジ)なるほど
先ほどと理屈は同じだな。
I see...
It's the same theory as earlier.
点穴がふさがれている。
こちらは数が多いがな。
The Chakra Points are closed.
There are more Chakra Points
here though...
皆 少し離れていてくれ。
Everyone, please stand back!
まだ助かる。
医療班に連れていこう。
We can still save him.
Let's take him to the Medical Team.
はい わかりました！
Yes, understood!
礼を言う。
ネジ お前に助けられるとは。
You have my thanks, Neji.
Imagine, being rescued by you.
フン。
皆さんは大丈夫ですか？
Is everyone all right?!
ああ もう平気っすよ。
Yes, we're okay now.
我愛羅様 ご無事で何よりです！
Lord Gaara!
Thank goodness you're safe!
マツリのヤツも立派に働いた。
うん。
Matsuri performed admirably too.
(紅)あそこに…。
Over there!
どうやら我々が
手を貸すまでもないようだな。
It seems like they don't need
our help, after all!
ああ ひと足遅かったようだ。
Yes, I guess we were
a little too late.
(フウ)滝隠れのフウっす！
I'm Fuu of the Hidden Waterfall!
アッシ 百人の友を作ってるっす。
I'm trying to make
one hundred friends!
だから フウの友達に
なってほしいっす！
So please, be Fuu's friend!
わかった わかった。
わかったから この手を離せ。
O-Okay, okay!
I get it, just let go of my hand.
ハハハ！ ネジ よかったですね！
Neji! You're so lucky!
(フウ)ヤッホ ヤッホホー！ 友達 友達！
Woohoo! Woohoo!
Friends! Friends!
hitori ja nai yo
You're not alone
osoreru mono nante nai kara
There's nothing to be afraid of
ikou saa me o ake te
Let's go, now open your eyes
butsukatte ita
I was crashing into you
hontou wa oitsuki taku te
I just wanted to catch up so badly
kizutsuke atte
We hurt one another
tsunagi tomeru kizuna hoshiku te
I just wanted a bond to connect me to you
"gomen" wasure nai de
"I'm sorry" Don't forget
shinji te matte te
Trust in me and wait
mukae ni ikun da
I'll come for you
yuuki no tomoshibi terashidase yowa sa o
The light of courage, reveal our weaknesses
kizu datte itami datte wakeae ba heiki da
If we share our wounds and pain, we'll be fine
kimi no senaka osu musun da yakusoku
This is the promise I made you push you forward
itsu datte hanare tatte
No matter when, even if we're apart
shinjirareru kizuna wa mune ni nemutteru
The bond I believe in rests in my heart
There was a time I felt the wounds
that I inflicted on my people
would never heal.
I thought I should just disappear
from the Sand Village.
(松丸)オープニングは 旅立ちの時から
今年で30年となった→
But I found there were people who,
without any prejudice,
accepted my feelings.
坂本九さんの名曲から
スタートしましょう。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Hopes Entrusted to the Future."
(宮本)菅原洋一さん
あおい輝彦さん→
氷川きよしさんに
歌っていただきます。
It is a youthful power,
one that supports the future.